Finding Aid for Paul Blanshard Papers, 1912-1979
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Julia Anderson Blanshard circa 1920-1939
  - Newspaper articles written by Julia Anderson Blanshard 1920s-1930s (Box 30)
    [30-1]
  - Newspaper articles written by Julia Anderson Blanshard 1920s-1930s (Box 30)
    (including observations of life in Russia and nudist camps in Germany)
    [30-2]
- Mary Hillyer Blanshard 1924-1965
  The Mary Hillyer Blanshard series covers the period of 1924 to 1965 and is composed of correspondence, articles, speeches, and subject files. This series is especially valuable for its documentation of Mary Hillyer Blanshard's political involvement and her championship of organized labor and other progressive causes. Of note are files pertaining to her interest in the International Ladies Garment Workers Union. The researcher will find here strike pamphlets, newsletters, and a history of the shirt workers union. There is also material about the Keep Out of War Congress.
  - Correspondence
    - Undated, A-H (Box 30)
      [30-3]
    - Undated, J-Z (Box 30)
      [30-4]
    - 1924-1929 (Box 30)
      [30-5]
    - 1930-1933 (Box 30)
      [30-6]
    - 1934-1939 (Box 30)
      [30-7]
    - 1940 (Box 30)
      [30-8]
    - 1941-1942 (Box 30)
      [30-9]
    - 1943-1957 (Box 30)
      [30-10]
    - 1960-1961 (Box 30)
      [30-11]
    - 1962 (Box 30)
      [30-12]
    - 1963-1964 (Box 30)
      [30-13]
    - 1965 (Box 30)
      [30-14]
  - Articles
    [30-15]
    - "Crisis in Labor: Industrial Versus Craft Unionism" 1936 (Box 30)
    - "Is This Our War?" 1940 (Box 30)
    - "Stop Hitler Now and Here" 1941 (Box 30)
    - "Can Government Solve the Problem of Poverty?" 1941 (Box 30)
    - "Italy and Birth Control" 1951 (Box 30)
    - "The White House Conference on Children and Youth" 1960 (Box 30)
    - "From the Inside, Looking Out" 1962 (Box 30)
    - "Capitol Hill Drama--SRO!" 1962 (Box 30)
  - Speeches
    [30-16]
    - "Labor Organizing" 1920s (Box 30)
    - "Better Business Relations" 1930 (Box 30)
    - "Acts of Tyranny and Terror" 1930s (Box 30)
    - Remarks concerning Post-War World Council 1942 (Box 30)
    - Statement before Special Senate Committee on Education 1959 (Box 30)
    - Sermonette before Unitarians 1961 (Box 30)
    - "Negroes Want to be Treated Like Men" 1962 (Box 30)
    - "Unitarians in Government" 1962 (Box 30)
  - International Ladies Garment Workers Union Local no. 38: Custom Dressmakers Union
    - Strike pamphlets 1920s-1930s, 2 folders (Box 30)
      [30-17; 30-18]
    - Newsletters 1920s-1930s (Box 30)
      [30-19]
    - Strike agreements, song, review of progress (Box 30)
      [30-20]
    - Miscellaneous (Box 30)
      [30-21]
    - Clippings and Bread and Roses: The Story of the Rise of the Shirt Workers (Box 30)
      [30-22]
    - "Close Up of the Clothing Industry" (Box 30)
      [30-23]
    - Notes on organization campaign among Troy, N.Y. Shirtworkers 1934 (Box 30)
      [30-24]
  - Socialist Party
    - Conventions
      - 1932, 1934, 1935 (Box 30)
        [30-25]
      - 1936 Convention, 2 folders (Box 30)
        [30-26; 30-27]
    - Miscellaneous printed 1930s (Box 30)
      [30-28]
    - Miscellaneous materials on League for Industrial Democracy 1930s (Box 30)
      [30-29]
    - GM-UAW Strike, Flint 1937
      - The Flint Auto Worker, Socialist Call, The I.M.A. News, The Advance, February 1937 (Box 30)
        [30-30]
      - "Punch Press" (official strike bulletin) February 1937 (Box 30)
        [30-31]
      - News releases, songs and miscellanea (Box 30)
        [30-32]
    - Miscellaneous CIO pamphlets (Box 30)
      [30-33]
    - Miscellaneous on liberal and radical movements (Box 30)
      [30-34]
  - Keep America Out of War Congress
    - News releases February-November, 1941 (Box 30)
      [30-35]
    - Pamphlets (Box 30)
    - Mary Hillyer Blanshard speeches and Speaker's Handbook (Box 30)
      [30-36]
    - Memoranda, resolutions and reports (Box 30)
      [30-37]
    - Printed materials (Box 30)
      [30-38]
    - Clippings (Box 30)
      [30-39]
  - Various other interests and activities
    - Post-War World Council 1942 miscellanea (Box 30)
      [30-40]
    - Printed and clippings 1947 on Springfield, Massachusetts birth control controversy (Box 30)
      [30-41]
    - Printed and miscellanea 1954 concerning Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America (New England) (Box 30)
      [30-42]
    - Unitarian Action (Mary Hillyer Blanshard, ed.), November 1958-February 1962 (Box 30)
      [30-43]
    - Unitarian Fellowship for Social Justice-miscellaneous printed (Box 30)
      [30-44]
  - Clippings/biographical
    - Clippings 1930s (Box 30)
      [30-45]
    - Clippings, Blanshard-Hillyer marriage 1935 (Box 30)
      [30-46]
    - Clippings 1940s (Box 30)
      [30-47]
    - Clippings 1950s (Box 30)
      [30-48]
    - Clippings 1960s (Box 30)
      [30-49]
    - Clippings, obituaries 1965 (Box 30)
      [30-50]
    - Biographical and genealogical information (Box 30)
      [30-51]
    - Scrapbook of articles written for The Christian Register, 1957-1962 and clippings (Box 30)
Selective index to the correspondence files of Paul Blanshard
Ad Hoc Committee to Lift Ban on The Nation.
December 6, 1948, December 2, 1948, February 5, 1949, July 13, 1949, December 6, 1949, June 16, 1950, June 26, 1950
Adler, Julius Ochs, 1892-1955.
May 19, 1949, June 8, 1949
Aiken, George David, 1892-
June 24, 1954
Allport, Gordon Willard, 1897-1967.
May 11, 1950
American Civil Liberties Union.
February 19, 1955, April 8, 1955, July 17, 1961, May 22, 1962, December 31, 1962
American Genetic Association.
September 7, 1951
American Humanist Association.
Letters throughout.
American Jewish Committee.
May 19, 1950, July 24, 1951, August 2, 1951, April 28, 1952, September 21, 1954, October 22, 1954, November 29, 1954, March 29, 1955, May 2, 1957, January 13, 1958, February 4, 1958, March 11, 1958, August 26, 1958, September 3, 1958, December 15, 1958, January 15, 1959, January 22. 1959, June 23, 1959, July 1, 1959, July 29, 1959, August 11, 1959, November 4, 1959, February 8, 1960, March 3, 1960, July 21, 1960, June 30, 1960, 1962, June 10, 1963, October 27, 1963
American Jewish Congress.
March 21, 1949, March 10, 1953, April 8, 1953, January 4, 1955, May 24, 1955, July 13, 1955, April 14, 1956, July 24, 1956, April 24, 1957, August 6, 1957, August 13, 1957, December 30, 1958, February 11, 1959, November 23, 1959, February 18, 1963, February, 24, 1965, June 1, 1965, January 17, 1966, May 3, 1966, May 10, 1966, July 12, 1966, March 15, 1968, March 19, 1968, June 24, 1968
Amory, Cleveland, 1917-
September 18, 1954
Anderson, Jack Northman, 1922-
August 3, 1953
Argoff, Charles, 1902-
January 3, 1950
Archer, Glenn Leroy, 1906-
September 1, 1949, September 26, 1949, November 22, 1949, December 14, 1949, December 18, 1950, 1951, April 16, 1953, May 25, 1953, June 2, 1953, October 2, 1953, November 5, 1953, August 19, 1954, January 27, 1955, March 15, 1955, March 21, 1955, April 7, 1955, May 2, 1955, August 30, 1955, September 12, 1956., June 12, 1957, August 12, 1957, June 2, 1958, June 3, 1958, June 17, 1958, August 12, 1958, August 29, 1958, September 2, 1958, September 26, 1958, April 30, 1959, September 27, 1961, July 10, 1962, November 21, 1963, August 5, 1964, August 28, 1964, September 4, 1964, March 16, 1965, May, 1967, November 20, 1968
Arnold, Melvin Luxton, 1913-
Letters throughout.
Arthur, William Bolling, 1914-
November 1, 1963
Axtelle, George, 1893-
April 11, 1958, April 17, 1958
Bain, Read, 1892-
September 1, 1959
Bartlett, Harley Harris, 1886-1960.
December 9, 1949
Beacon Press.
Letters throughout.
Bennett, Wallace Foster, 1898-
June 20, 1963
Benson, Ezra Taft, 1899-
September 23, 1960
Biddle, Francis, 1886-1968.
March 8, 1945
Birkhead, Leon Milton, 1885-1954.
June 29, 1949
Blanshard, Brand, 1892-
July 23, 1948, December 9, 1948, January 26, 1949, December 21, 1950 June 15, 1951, July 25, 1951, April 20, 1952, May 24, 1953, November 1, 1953, November 20, 1953, January 10, 1954, August 9, 1954, August 27, 1954, December 15, 1954, January 4, 1955, July 31, 1955, March 23, 1956, April 27, 1956, May 20, 1956, July 2, 1956, August 22, 1956, August 26, 1956, October 6, 1956, undated, 1957, May 1, 1957, December 30, 1957, January 7, 1958, March 2, 1958, August 16, 1958, September 3, 1958, November 8, 1958, January 13, 1959, January 25, 1959, November 23, 1959, December 27, 1959, March 13, 1960, July 8, 1960, October 12, 1960, December 31, 1960, February 19, 1961, August 23, 1961, September 3, 1961, January 8, 1962, March 5, 1962, April 11, 1962, June 12, 1962, July 5, 1962, August 29, 1962, December 19, 1962, January 9, 1963, May 31, 1963, July 18, 1963, October 27, 1963, December 16, 1963, April 20, 1964, June 22, 1964, August 17, 1964 August 31, 1964, October 29, 1964, December 18, 1964, January 27, 1965, April 3, 1965, January 30, 1966, May 12, 1966, July 7, 1966, August 27, 1966, December 11, 1966, January 3, 1967, February 9, 1967, April 24, 1967, July 16, 1967, September 8, 1967, September 27, 1967, January 1, 1968, January 12, 1968, February 18, 1968, February 27, 1968, April 3, 1968, May 30, 1968, December 15, 1968, January 11, 1969, March 2, 1969, May 1, 1969, May 9, 1969, May 22, 1969
Blanshard, Mary (Hillyer), -1965.
See Mary (Hillyer) Blanshard Inventory.
Bowie, Walter Russell, 1882-1969.
August 29, 1949
Brameld, Theodore, 1904-
January 3, 1954
Brown, Francis, 1903-
May 9, 1962
Bunche, Ralph Johnson, 1904-1971.
October 25, 1947, November 21, 1960
Burdett, Winston, 1913-
January 1, 1965, April 21, 1965, July 4, 1965, June 27, 1966
Burns, James MacGregor, 1918-
December 8, 1959
Caldwell, John Tyler, 1911-
February 16, 1959
Chalmers, Allan Knight, 1897-
December 15, 1954
Chambers, David Laurance, 1879-1963.
April 13, 1948
Clothier, Florence, 1903-
April 17, 1951
Cogley, John, 1916-
March 23, 1953, April 20, 1953, March 26, 1958, May 14, 1958, May 26, 1958, November 20, 1967
Collier, John, 1884-1968.
November 9, 1947
Cousins, Norman, 1912-
July 12, 1949, June 12, 1953, June 3, 1954, May 21, 1958, May 14, 1962, September 27, 1967
Cowley, William Harold, 1899-
March 27, 1948
Dawson, Joseph M., 1879-
June 22, 1953
Dewey, John, 1859-1952.
June 7, 1949
Dickinson, Robert Latou, 1861-1950.
June 18, 1948, October 22, 1948, October 28, 1948, April 19, 1949
Douglas, Paul Howard, 1892-
May 22, 1957, September 8, 1965, May 6, 1969
Einstein, Albert, 1879-1955.
July 19, 1951
Eliot, Frederick May, 1889-1958.
June 20, 1949, February 20, 1956
Evans, Bergen, 1904-
November 24, 1947
Fairchild, Henry Pratt, 1880-1956.
May 19, 1949, May 18, 1951
Fey, Harold E., 1898-
April 9, 1953, June 10, 1954, November 4, 1958
Fischer, John, 1910-
June 8, 1949, November 1, 1957, January 8, 1963, March 13, 1963
Flanders, Ralph Edward, 1880-1970.
August 12, 1957
Foote, Henry Wilder, 1875-1964.
January 14, 1954
Ford, Gerald Rudolph, 1913-
June 19, 1956
Freethinkers of America.
June 14, 1948, April 6, 1955
Friends of Democracy, Inc.
June 29, 1949, October 25, 1949
Gallup, George Horace, 1901-
May 9, 1958
Gannett, Lewis Stiles, 1891-1966.
March 18, 1948, June 3, 1954
Gibson, Ernest William, 1901-1969.
March 1, 1949
Givens, Willard Earl, 1886-1971.
January 24, 1949, May 6, 1949
Goldman, Eric Frederick, 1915-
April 28, 1956, June 19, 1956
Greeley, Dana McLean, 1908-
August 29, 1963, March 9, 1966
Gruening, Ernest, 1887-
May 8, 1963, February 22, 1965, April 28, 1965
Gunther, John, 1901-
September 25, 1961
Hall, Frank A., 1894-1972.
December 11, 1951
Hardman, J. B. S.
July 9, 1951, July 13, 1951
Harrington, Donald
August 8, 1949, December 21, 1951, June 25, 1956, April 27, 1966
Harrison, Gilbert A., 1915-
December 1, 1959, December 16, 1959
Hartman, Carl G., 1879-1968.
September 25, 1951
Hays, Arthur Garfield, 1881-1954.
January 5, 1950
Hechinger, Fred Michael, 1920-
February 20, 1961
Henry, Carl Ferdinand Howard, 1913-
December 4, 1958, December 9, 1958
Holmes, John Haynes, 1879-1964.
April 11, 1949, April 20, 1949, July 23, 1960
Human Betterment Association of America, Inc.
January 14, 1953
Hunt, Alma, 1909-
June 4, 1953
Hutchins, Robert Maynard, 1899-
June 11, 1954
Hutchinson, Paul, 1890-1956.
May 27, 1949, June 3, 1949, August 9, 1949, April 20, 1953, May 19, 1953
Huxley, Julian, 1887-1975.
September 7, 1951, June 14, 1954
Independent Voters for Norman Thomas.
September 2, 1948
Institute of Ethnic Affairs.
November 9, 1947
International Committee on Planned Parenthood.
May 30, 1952
International Planned Parenthood Federation.
November 23, 1953, December 7, 1953, April 26, 1961
James, Edwin Leland, 1890-1951.
October 14, 1948
Jones, Bob, 1911-
December 6, 1958
Jones, Howard Mumford, 1892-
December 9, 1956
Kallen, Horace Meyer, 1882-
November 18, 1958
Kennedy, John Fitzgerald, 1917-1963.
January 13, 1958, February 14, 1958, April 24, 1958, April 29, 1959, February 10, 1961
Kirchwey, Freda
October 23, 1947, January 28, 1948, January 16, 1948, March 5, 1948, May 24, 1950, May 31, 1951, September 12, 1951, September 19, 1951, November 6, 1953, June 14, 1954, July 9, 1954, March 16, 1965
Kirstein, George Garland, 1909-
August 5, 1958
Knopf, Alfred A., 1892-
November 6, 1947, November 17, 1947, December 24, 1947
Kunstler, William Moses, 1919-
June 4, 1958, January 29, 1960
LaGuardia, Fiorella Henry, 1882-1947.
October 16, 1942
Lamont, Corliss, 1902-
March 16, 1956, June 27, 1956, April 6, 1957, May 17, 1957, May 28, 1957, June 18, 1957, April 14, 1958, November 4, 1958
LaPiana, George, 1879-1971.
September 23, 1948, October 25, 1948, February 27, 1949, March 1, 1949, May 6, 1950, June 12, 1950, January 26, 1951, February 19, 1951, September 18, 1951, December 28, 1951
Lasker, Bruno, 1880-1965.
October 10, 1954, February 11, 1955
Latham, Harold Strong, 1887-1969.
November 29, 1950
Lathrop, John Howland, 1880-1967.
March 15, 1949
League for Fair Play.
November 4, 1947
Lee, Alfred McClung, 1906-
June 8, 1955, April 23, 1963
Leiper, Henry Smith, 1891-
July 23, 1948, April 22, 1949, October 31, 1951, January 4, 1952, June 4, 1958, February 10, 1959
Lerner, Max, 1902-
March 22, 1958
Lewis, Anthony, 1927-
January 3. 1960
Lipphard, William Benjamin, 1886-1971.
June 20, 1949,. September 21, 1949
Livingston, Goodhue, 1867-1951.
December 2, 1958
Lodge, John Davis, 1903-
July 31, 1959
Lord, John Wesley, 1902-
July 19, 1966
Luce, Henry Robinson, 1898-1967.
August 9, 1949
Lyons, Louis, 1897-
December 11, 1962
McGraw, Harold Whittlesey, 1918-
February 26, 1958
MacGregor, Frank Silver, 1897-1971.
November 20, 1951, January 31, 1952
MacKay, John Alexander, 1889-
January 22, 1951
MacLeish, Archibald, 1892-
December 2, 1948
Mallett, Reginald, 1893-1965.
April 13, 1960
Matthews, Herbert Lionel, 1900-
March 13, 1961
Miller, Clyde R., 1888-
November 4, 1947, November 6, 1947, December 4, 1947
Moehlman, Conrad Henry, 1879-
July 10, 1951
Monroney, Aimer Stillwell (Mike), 1902-
February 10, 1960
Moore, Hugh, 1887-1972.
January 30, 1962
Muller, Hermann Joseph, 1890-1967.
August 20, 1951, October 23, 1951
Muste, Abraham John, 1885-1967.
October 15, 1953
Nader, Ralph, 1934-
August 27, 1958, September 18, 1958
National Council on Freedom From Censorship.
November 30, 1953
Neuberger, Maurine Brown, 1907-
October 8, 1963, September 9, 1965
O'Dwyer, William, 1890-1964.
July 26, 1948
Oxnam, Garfield Bromley, 1891-1963.
November 11, 1947, January 15, 1948, June 27, 1949, September 22, 1949, December 19, 1949, June 10, 1959
Peal, Norman Vincent, 1898-
September 15, 1960
Pearson, Drew, 1897-1969.
September 2, 1949
Phillips, Thomas Wharton, 1874-1956.
December 19, 1949, October 8, 1951
Pike, James Albert, 1913-1969.
February 7, 1955, December 16, 1959, December 30, 1959, April 28, 1960, December 6, 1962
Pitkin, Walter Boughton, 1878-1953.
October 4, 1951
Planned Parenthood Federation of America, Inc.
April 9, 1947, April 25, 1947, May 8, 1947, June 23, 1947, July 1, 1947, July 25, 1947, August 20, 1947, July 21, 1947, September 16, 1947, November 12, 1947, May 11, 1948, June 24, 1948, October 18, 1948, June 20, 1951, August 9, 1951, December 28, 1953, January 11, 1954, March 4, 1954. April 2, 1957, June 12, 1957, November 9, 1960
Poling, Daniel Alfred, 1884-1968.
November 28, 1956, November 29, 1956, December 5, 1956, February 3, 1960
Poteat, Edwin McNeill, 1892-1955.
August 23, 1948, January 18, 1951, December 3, 1951
Potofsky, Jacob, 1894-
January 8, 1954
Protestants and Other Americans United for Separation of Church and State.
April 29, 1948, September 1, 1949, September 26, 1949, November 22, 1949, December 14, 1949, December 18, 1950, 1951, March 6, 1953, May 8, 1953, May 25, 1953, August 10, 1953, October 2, 1953, November 5, 1953, June 9, 1954, December 29, 1954, 1955, July 25, 1956, September 12, 1956, May 31, 1957, July 5, 1957, July 31, 1957, August 6, 1957, August 12, 1957, 1958, February 20, 1959, March 4, 1959, April 30, 1959, June 23, 1960, June 30, 1960, August 5, 1960, September 26, 1960, 1961, 1962, February 18, 1963, November 21, 1963, November 27, 1963, August 5, 1964, August 17, 1964, August 28, 1964, September 4, 1964, December 15, 1964, February 1, 1965, March 5, 1965, March 15, 1965, March 16, 1965, 1966, May, 1967, July 20, 1967, 1968, February 11, 1969, February 12, 1969, June 2, 1969
Raines, Richard Campbell, 1898-
October 9, 1950
Rice, Paul North, 1888-1967.
June 28, 1948
Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962.
March 22, 1958
Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, 1882-1945.
August 4, 1933
Rose, David Kenneth, 1902-1963.
April 9, 1947, April 25, 1947, May 8, 1947, June 23, 1947, July 1, 1947, July 25, 1947, September 16, 1947, November 12, 1947, May 11, 1948, October 18, 1948
Rugg, Harold, 1886-1960.
September 13, 1955
Russell, Bertrand, 1872-1970.
April 21, 1951, April 15, 1953, May 15, 1953, November 10, 1953, July 2, 1958
Sanger, Margaret, -1966.
July 30, 1951, November 23, 1953, December 7, 1953
Saxe, Karl, 1892-
July 9, 1951
Schlesinger, Arthur Meier, 1917-
August 8, 1956
Schroeder, John Charles, 1897-1954.
January 7, 1950
Seabury, Samuel, 1873-1958.
December 31, 1937
Sheen, Fulton John, 1895-
July 29, 1948
Shipler, Guy Emery, 1881-
September 21, 1949
Sinclair, Upton, 1878-1968.
October 13, 1948, August 29, 1949, April 7, 1955, April 2, 1956
Society for Ethical Culture (New York).
October 9, 1946, August 5, 1949, August 23, 1949, September 15, 1949, October 31, 1951, September 28, 1953
Sorensen, Theodore Chaikin, 1928-
March 14, 1960, April 12, 1960, May 3, 1961, November 6, 1961
Spivak, Lawrence Edmund
October 15, 1947, October 27, 1947, June 29, 1949
Stein, Robert, 1924-
July 9, 1962
Stokes, Anson Phelps, 1874-1958.
August 23, 1949
Stout, Rex, 1886-
June 4, 1957, August 27, 1957, March 6, 1958
Stuber, Stanley Irving, 1903-
December 10, 1964
Sulzberger, Arthur Hays, 1891-1968.
May 10, 1949
Susskind, David Howard, 1920-
March 17, 1960
Taft, Charles Phelps, 1897-
December 15, 1958
Tate, Jack B., 1902-
June 8, 1953
Taussig, Charles William, 1896-1948.
May 16, 1945, August 6, 1945, September 16, 1947
Tead, Ordway, 1891-
August 4, 1950
Terman, Lewis Madison, 1877-1956.
July 3, 1951
Thayer, Walter Nelson, 1910-
December 31, 1962
Thomas, Norman Mattoon, 1884-1968.
December, 1948, September 24, 1951, October 8, 1951, November 6, 1953, November, 1954, December 19, 1955, November 26, 1956, November 15, 1956, June 26, 1957, July 9, 1957, August 12, 1957, April 25, 1958, January 26, 1960, August 26, 1962, July 17, 1963, February 26, 1965, June 21, 1965, August 12, 1965, September 4, 1965, January 20, 1966, March 21, 1966
Ulich, Robert, 1890-
August 31, 1951, September 25, 1951
Van Dusen, Henry Pitney, 1897-
July 8, 1966
Viereck, Peter, 1916-
September 10, 1951, October 3, 1951
Wakefield, Sherman Day, 1894-1971.
June 26, 1948, August 29, 1948
Warren, Earl, 1891-1974.
January 6, 1960
Weeks, Edward Augustus, 1898-
November 7, 1949, December 8, 1949, December 15, 1949, April 29, 1953, April 29, 1955, July 20, 1956
Wendt, Gerald, 1891-
February 4, 1960, June 11, 1960, September 11, 1960, September 12, 1960, September 16, 1960, July 10, 1962, December 21, 1962, December 31, 1962, September 29, 1963, November 27, 1963, February 29, 1964
Whitaker, Arthur, 1895-
May 7, 1962
Williams, Charl Ormond, 1885-
September 1, 1949, September 9, 1949
Woodfolk, Josiah Pitts (Jack Woodford), 1894-
October 25, 1949
Wylie, Philip Gordon, 1902-1971.
August 6, 1949
Yerkes, Robert Mearns, 1876-1956.
June 22, 1949, July 31, 1949, September 26, 1951
Selective index to the correspondence files of Mary Hillyard Blanshard
Affiliated Summer Schools for Women Workers in Industry
March 5, 1930
America First Committee
November 27, 1940
Blanshard, Brand, 1892-
March 13, 1965
Bliven, Bruce, 1889-
March 17, 1927
Broun, Heywood, 1888-1939.
February 6, 1930, September 3, 1930
Chamberlin, William Henry
Undated
Conference for Progressive Labor Action.
September 21, 1929
Dewey, John, 1859-1952.
October, 1933, February 16, 1938.
Douglas, Emily
Undated, 7 items, December 25, 1964, March 20, 1965
Douglas, Paul Howard, 1892-
March 12, 1965
Edwards, George, 1914-
April 6, 1965
Flynn, John Thomas, 1882-1964.
October 28, 1942
Gilbert, Charles Kendall, 1878-1958.
May 27, 1930
Green, William, 1870-1952?
November 17, 1928
Gruening, Ernest, 1887
August 21, 1963
Holmes, John Haynes, 1879-1964.
April 15, 1957, July 23, 1960, August 8, 1961, July 2, 1962
Humphrey, Hubert Horatio, 1911-
May 16, 1960
Keep America Out of War Congress.
September 9, 1941, November 21, 1941
Kirchwey, Freda
Undated, 8 items
Landon, Alfred Mossman, 1887-
October 27, 1942
League of Women Shoppers
February 5, 1937
Lee, Jennie
June 1, 1940, July 26, 1940, August 15, 1940, October 22, 1940, June 23, 1951, August 30, 1951, July 18, 1957, May 4, 1961, October 9, 1962, September 25, 1962, October 30, 1962, September 13, 1962, February 21, 1963, November 19, 1963, June 25, 1964, November 11, 1964, March 23, 1965
Lovett, Robert Morss, 1870-1956.
January 21, 1941
Mencken, Henry Louis, 1880-1956.
March 9, 1942, March 12, 1942, March 16, 1942, March 24, 1942
Muste, Abraham John, 1885-1967.
September 21, 1929, April 12, 1931
Neuberger, Maurine Brown, 1907-
Undated, 3 items, February 14, 1960, October 2, 1962, October 31, 1962, November 7, 1963, May 7, 1964
Non-Partisan Committee for Harry W. Laidler for City Council.
October 28, 1937
Planned Parenthood Federation of America, Inc.
August 20, 1963
Post War World Council.
November 10, 1942, November 28, 1949
Reuther, Victor George, 10,12
March 22, 1965
Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962.
1930
Sanger, Margaret, -1966.
August 8, 1951
Schlesinger, Arthur Meier, 1917-
March 14, 1965
Shapiro, Rose
May 26, 1936
Sorensen, Theodore Chaikin, 1928-
November 3, 1961
Stevenson, Adlai Ewing, 1900-1965.
November 3, 1961
Thomas, Norman Mattoon, 1884-1968.
Undated, 2 items, March 17, 1938, March 19, 1938, November 14, 1940, November 28, 1949, July 24, 1960, August 9, 1960, November 4, 1964, November 9, 1964
Vallee, Rudy, 1901-
October 2, 1930
Villard, Oswald Garrison, 1872-1947.
Undated, October 23, 1942, November 30, 1942